

# **Gideon Pinto**

# Software Engineer



# **Summary**



A Software Engineer with a designer's eye and a creative spirit. Skilled in JavaScript, Python and developing intuitive user experiences. Strong engineering professional background with a Master's Degree focused on Digital Media & Design from Northeastern.



# **Experience**

### 2015-06 -2016-09

# **Content Development and Acquisition Editor**

- Reviewed the drafts delivered by authors and provided feedback on the content
- Proofread the code and fixed errors through collaborations with external technical reviewers
- Trained and mentored newly joined candidates on delivery of feedback and code testing
- Designed the course curriculum for books and online videos on JavaScript and Java

# 2019-04 -

# present

# Front End Developer Intern

#### **Incluvie**

- Working with Incluvie as a part of Northeastern's XN program for credits.
- Fleshing out new functionalities for Incluvie's website which gives you the diversity quotient of a particular movie.
- Developing bits and pieces of the UI using React, Redux which includes 'Add to watch later' and 'Add to favorite' lists, Login and Register Forms with Modals and their subsequent validations in Firebase.



### **Education**

2017-09 present

# Northeastern University

#### Masters of Science, Digital Media and Design

Relevant Coursework: Programming Foundations in JavaScript, Web Creation Bootcamp, Web App Design and Development, Intermediate Programming, Foundations in Digital Storytelling

#### 2011-08 -2015-09

# St Francis Institute of Technology

#### **Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science**

Relevant Coursework: Algorithms and Data Structures, Fundamentals of Java Programming, Mobile Application Development, Advanced Database Management Systems



# Academic Projects

#### 2019-01

# CraftMonkey with React, GraphQL, and Prisma

- Created a full stack online clothing store which allows users to search, customize, add to cart and checkout their favorite items.
- Implemented server side functionalities including JWT Authentication, permissions, sending email's, uploading images and charging credit cards. Built the app around relational data models using GraphQL and wrote subsequent mutation and queries.

#### 2019-01

### **DevSocial using the MERN Stack**

- Created a social media website with an extensive back-end API in Express, Node and MongoDB. Used the Passport JWT Strategy and Validator for authentication.
- Created the front end of the application using React and Redux. Created reducers and actions for the application's resources and developed container components that integrated with Redux.

#### 2019-02

#### Think Piece with React and Firebase

- Create a fully-featured Blog Application using React and Cloud Firestore. Leveraged the cloud functions to render the UI in response to the changes in the database.
- Implemented access control and data validations for the documents in the database using security rules. Managed the state using React's Context API and deployed it to the cloud using the Firebase CLI.

### 2018-12

API to hit.

- Dashboard application for in-house projects using Angular Core • Used the Angular CLI and Nrwl Schematics to build the bare-bones of the application. The app was built using components, templates, forms, routes and a JSON server as a fake REST
- Implemented the CRUD functionalities for the projects with forms using Angular Material to leverage its in-built interaction patterns.

### 2018-12

# Data Visualization for Northeastern's Health Lab (Experiential Learning)

- Wrote an AWS lambda function in Node which interfaced with the fitbit API and authenticated Xvalve to fetch user's data via the OAuth2.0 workflow
- Used the Subscriptions API from fitbit to notify Xvalve of new user data. Fetched user data at 15 minutes granularity using "the Intraday Access" permission and stored them in the MongoDB database



#### E-mail

pinto.gi@husky.neu.edu

#### Website

gideonpinto.com/portfolio

#### **GitHub**

https://github.com/PintoGideon



#### **Skills**

<u>Programming Languages:</u> JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, Python, HTML, CSS/Sass

<u>Libraries and Frameworks:</u> React, Angular, GraphQL, jQuery, Node, D3, Gatsby

Tools and Platforms: Git, Gulp, Grunt, Netlify, GraphQL, Prismic, Craft, Wordpress, Docker

<u>Design:</u> Sketch, InVision, InDesign